NATHAN HAMILTON

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

615.604.8814 NATHAN.A.HAMILTON@GMAIL.COM HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/NATHANROMAD WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/NATHAN-ANDREW-HAMILTON

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- VS CODE

- Bootstrap
- Python
- SQL

- JSON Server
- Flgma

PROFILE

A world traveler, business manager, and software developer with an insatiable intellectual curiosity, passion for problem solving, as well as highly detail oriented. My goal is to utilize my diverse experiences in business as a software developer and continue to learn new ways in which software development can solve real world problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | 2021 - Present

- 6 month Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript, React, Python, Django
- · Git & Github codebase & task management
- Collaborative coding & solo app development

RESTAURANT MANAGER

Henley Nashville | 2019 - 2021 - Nashville, TN

• Responsible for managing and organizing daily restaurant operations with a goal of controlling costs and providing a high quality experience to customers.

GENERAL MANAGER / CONSULTANT

Never Never | 2019 - Nashville, TN

• Inventory, hiring, training, and overseeing staff, maintaining a budget, managing operations, taking bar inventory, conducting marketing, restaurant SEO, bar promotion, and driving sales.

LEAD BARTENDER

Hemingway's Bar & Hideaway | 2017-2019 - Nashville, TN

• Responsible for ensuring bar operation runs efficiently, inventory, and managing other bartenders.

MARKETING TEAM MEMBER

Bernard Health | 2017 - Nashville, TN

- Develop and qualify new sales opportunities. Schedule product demos & discovery calls for account
- Utilize effective email and telephone communication techniques. Maintain prospect and client records database.

OPERATIONS MANAGER

Park Nashville | 2016 - Nashville, TN

- Manage operations of daily tasks, build and keep up the schedule, payroll, time-punches, and material management for more than a dozen accounts and personnel of 65+.
- Preserve positive relationships with clients while maintaining high level results in a fast paced and ever changing environment. M*Street - main account.

FUEL OPERATOR

Pacific Architects and Engineers (PAE) - McMurdo Station, Antarctica | 2012-2013 & 2014-2015

- Provide assistance to all grantees and other agencies in support of National Science Foundation
- Perform fuel transfers, aircraft refueling, fuel testing, maintenance and operation of fuels facilities for McMurdo Station and remote field stations.

NATHAN HAMILTON

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PROJECTS

topFIVE | Mar 2021

- Full-stack one page application for keeping track of your topFIVE's!
- This application will allow a user to log in and create, read, update, or delete their topFIVE's.
- A user will be able to 'follow' other users topFIVE's.

HOLIDAY ROAD - ACCIDENTAL ENGINE

- Creating wireframes and Dependency diagrams
- Incorporating Agile framework and methodologies
- Technologies used; javascript, html and css, API's.

HELLO WORLD - TRAVEL COMPANY

This was our first group project at Nashville Software School, and we used HTML, CSS, Flexbox, JavaScript, Event Listeners, Git, Github, and http-server to build the website.

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL (NSS) - NASHVILLE, TN

Full-stack software development

2021

TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY (TSU) - NASHVILLE, TN

B.B.A in Economics & Finance 2012 Golden Key National Honor Society/Beta Gamma Sigma – GPA: 3.6 Emphasis: International Business (first TSU candidate for degree)

CENTER OF ACADEMIC EXCELLENCE IN INTELLIGENCE STUDIES

Tianjin; Shanghai; Beijing China 2011

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND UNIVERSITY COLLEGE

Camp Casey AIN/Dongducheon, South Korea

2004-2005

MILITARY SERVICE

Tactical Air Control Party Journeyman - Honorable Discharge

United States Air Force - United States (multiple locations) & South Korea

- · Performed liaison duties to ensure effective integration of Close Air Support (CAS) with aligned Army units.
- Create battle plans and perform reconnaissance of objectives, analyze information, mark and destroy targets of importance in order to support United States military missions.